[
    {
        "question": "What resource makes up the Earth’s geosphere?",
        "a": "ice",
        "b": "organisms",
        "c": "rock",
        "d": "air",
        "e": "water",
        "correct_answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "The cryosphere is part of the",
        "a": "biosphere",
        "b": "geosphere",
        "c": "lithosphere",
        "d": "atmosphere",
        "e": "hydrosphere",
        "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which atmospheric layer is CLOSEST to Earth’s surface?",
        "a": "stratosphere",
        "b": "thermosphere",
        "c": "exosphere",
        "d": "mesosphere",
        "e": "troposphere",
        "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
        "question": "Certain gases cause the greenhouse gas effect because they are",
        "a": "transparent",
        "b": "abundant",
        "c": "reflective",
        "d": "dense",
        "e": "absorbent",
        "correct_answer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which external energy source is MOST vital to Earth?",
        "a": "tidal",
        "b": "solar",
        "c": "hydroelectric",
        "d": "wind",
        "e": "geothermal",
        "correct_answer": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "Most interactions between the geosphere and other subsystems take place within the Earth’s",
        "a": "inner core",
        "b": "lower mantle",
        "c": "outer core",
        "d": "upper mantle",
        "e": "crust",
        "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
        "question": "The term “lithosphere” incorporates the Greek word for",
        "a": "stone",
        "b": "soil",
        "c": "glacier",
        "d": "mist",
        "e": "breeze",
        "correct_answer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following natural cycles has faced rapid acceleration from the use of fossil fuels?",
        "a": "phosphorous",
        "b": "carbon",
        "c": "nitrogen",
        "d": "water",
        "e": "sulfur",
        "correct_answer": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "What scientific approach views the Earth's land, oceans, and atmosphere as a single structure?",
        "a": "atmospheric science",
        "b": "environmental science",
        "c": "geospatial science",
        "d": "earth system science",
        "e": "oceanography",
        "correct_answer": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "A meteorological rocket would MOST likely be found in the",
        "a": "troposphere",
        "b": "stratosphere",
        "c": "exosphere",
        "d": "mesosphere",
        "e": "thermosphere",
        "correct_answer": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "To which of the following subsystems would a fossilized human belong?",
        "a": "atmosphere",
        "b": "hydrosphere",
        "c": "geosphere",
        "d": "biosphere",
        "e": "cryosphere",
        "correct_answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "All of the following aspects of climate change focus on the hydrosphere EXCEPT",
        "a": "air moisture depletion",
        "b": "sea level rise",
        "c": "severe droughts",
        "d": "melting ice",
        "e": "warming oceans",
        "correct_answer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "Scientists label feedbacks as either",
        "a": "internal or external",
        "b": "linear or exponential",
        "c": "constructive or destructive",
        "d": "dynamic or static",
        "e": "positive or negative",
        "correct_answer": "e"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following items would MOST likely appear in the troposphere?",
        "a": "radiosonde",
        "b": "spaceship",
        "c": "hot air balloon",
        "d": "satellite",
        "e": "aurora",
        "correct_answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which term refers to factors that influence climate change?",
        "a": "perturbations",
        "b": "alterations",
        "c": "fluctuations",
        "d": "modifiers",
        "e": "forcings",
        "correct_answer": "e"
    }
]
